Hi everyone, I'm Sahel and today with Hoseina Hivani, we are going to talk about instruction
안녕하세요 여러분, 저는 Sahel입니다. 오늘은 Hoseina Hivani와 함께 교육에 관해 이야기해보겠습니다.
training and reinforcement learning with human feedback.
인간의 피드백을 통한 훈련 및 강화 학습.
Language models are trained on large corpora using mostly unlabeled data from the web.
언어 모델은 웹에서 대부분 레이블이 지정되지 않은 데이터를 사용하여 대규모 말뭉치에 대해 훈련됩니다.
To keep the training process self-supervised, the objective is often the next token prediction
훈련 과정을 자체 감독하기 위해 목표는 종종 다음 토큰 예측입니다.
or some other language objectives, language masking objectives like denoising for birth,
또는 다른 언어 목표, 출생 시 잡음 제거와 같은 언어 마스킹 목표,
for example.
예를 들어.
With this setting, the output model learns word embeddings well and it might even do
이 설정을 사용하면 출력 모델이 단어 임베딩을 잘 학습하며 심지어 그렇게 할 수도 있습니다.
well for some NLP tasks that it's been exposed to during training.
훈련 중에 노출된 일부 NLP 작업에는 적합합니다.
However, the objective function during the training does not match the one at inference
그러나 훈련 중 목적 함수는 추론 시 목적 함수와 일치하지 않습니다.
time, which is to follow the human provided instructions.
인간이 제공한 지시를 따르는 시간입니다.
One common mitigation is to fine-tune the model for our desired task.
일반적인 완화 방법 중 하나는 원하는 작업에 맞게 모델을 미세 조정하는 것입니다.
As shown on the right-hand side figure, the limitation of this method is that it's task-specific
오른쪽 그림에서 볼 수 있듯이 이 방법의 한계는 작업별로 다르다는 것입니다.
and it often requires many examples.
그리고 종종 많은 예가 필요합니다.
The other solution is to rely on the language models in context learning ability and to
다른 해결책은 상황 학습 능력에서 언어 모델에 의존하고
provide a few examples of the desired task during inference.
추론 중에 원하는 작업에 대한 몇 가지 예를 제공합니다.
However, few-shot prompting often requires prompt engineering for an efficient learning
그러나 퓨샷 프롬프팅에는 효율적인 학습을 위해 신속한 엔지니어링이 필요한 경우가 많습니다.
and adding examples can make inference costly.
예제를 추가하면 추론 비용이 많이 들 수 있습니다.
And on top of that, you also have challenges because the context size is limited.
게다가 컨텍스트 크기가 제한되어 있기 때문에 어려움도 있습니다.
Today, I'm going to present three papers which propose to improve the performance of
오늘은 성능 향상을 제안하는 세 가지 논문을 발표하겠습니다.
language model zero-shot.
언어 모델 제로샷.
And by zero-shot here, I mean that language model hasn't seen the task before, not as
여기서 제로샷이란 언어 모델이 이전에 작업을 본 적이 없다는 것을 의미합니다.
an in-context example, nor during pre-training or fine-tuning.
상황에 맞는 예가 아니며, 사전 훈련이나 미세 조정 중에도 마찬가지입니다.
Let's start with the first paper, which is Flan from Google.
Google의 Flan이라는 첫 번째 논문부터 시작하겠습니다.
Flan authors define the term instruction training as fine-tuning the language model
Flan 저자는 교육 훈련이라는 용어를 언어 모델을 미세 조정하는 것으로 정의합니다.
on many tasks that are described via instruction in natural language.
자연어 교육을 통해 설명되는 많은 작업에 대해 설명합니다.
The idea is that by being exposed to many instructions, the model will learn to follow
모델은 많은 지침을 접함으로써 이를 따르는 법을 배우게 된다는 아이디어입니다.
the instructions and it will be able to generalize to unseen tasks.
지침을 제공하면 보이지 않는 작업으로 일반화할 수 있습니다.
And this method works well because many NLP tasks are describable via natural language
그리고 이 방법은 많은 NLP 작업이 자연어를 통해 설명 가능하기 때문에 잘 작동합니다.
instructions such as summarize the following program or translate the following sentence
다음 프로그램을 요약하거나 다음 문장을 번역하는 등의 지시 사항
from A to B. Let's walk through an example here.
A에서 B까지. 여기서 예를 살펴보겠습니다.
As I mentioned, fine-tuning involves training on multiple tasks at the same time.
앞서 언급했듯이 미세 조정에는 동시에 여러 작업에 대한 교육이 포함됩니다.
Here we have common sense reasoning, translation, and some other tasks.
여기에는 상식 추론, 번역 및 기타 작업이 있습니다.
The inference is zero-shot, meaning that it is on a task that is not used during training.
추론은 제로샷입니다. 즉, 훈련 중에 사용되지 않는 작업에 대한 추론입니다.
Here we have natural language inference and it doesn't have any in-context examples provided.
여기에는 자연어 추론이 있지만 상황에 맞는 예는 제공되지 않습니다.
And both during training and inference time tasks are described as instructions in natural
훈련 및 추론 시간 동안 작업은 모두 자연스러운 지침으로 설명됩니다.
language.
언어.
To create a dataset for instruction tuning, Flan authors categorize 62 NLP datasets into
명령어 튜닝을 위한 데이터 세트를 생성하기 위해 Flan 작성자는 62개의 NLP 데이터 세트를 다음과 같이 분류합니다.
12 clusters.
클러스터 12개.
Each cluster represents a task type.
각 클러스터는 작업 유형을 나타냅니다.
They use cluster granularity to determine whether or not a model has seen a task.
클러스터 세분성을 사용하여 모델이 작업을 확인했는지 여부를 결정합니다.
This is in contrast with using the dataset granularity.
이는 데이터 세트 세분성을 사용하는 것과 대조됩니다.
This means that Flan's performance on a dataset is considered to be evaluated zero-shot only
이는 데이터세트에 대한 Flan의 성능이 제로샷으로만 평가되는 것으로 간주됨을 의미합니다.
if no dataset from its cluster has been used during training or fine-tuning.
훈련 또는 미세 조정 중에 클러스터의 데이터 세트가 사용되지 않은 경우.
For each cluster, the authors train the model on the remaining 11 clusters and evaluated
각 클러스터에 대해 저자는 나머지 11개 클러스터에서 모델을 훈련하고 평가했습니다.
the model on the held-out cluster in a zero-shot setting.
제로 샷 설정에서 유지 클러스터의 모델입니다.
For each dataset, the authors compose 10 unique templates and to further diversify the prompts
각 데이터 세트에 대해 저자는 10개의 고유한 템플릿을 구성하고 프롬프트를 더욱 다양화합니다.
up to three of these templates were in reverse format.
이 템플릿 중 최대 3개는 역방향 형식이었습니다.
For example, asking a model to write a movie review for a given sentiment or a question
예를 들어, 모델에게 주어진 감정이나 질문에 대한 영화 리뷰를 작성하도록 요청합니다.
for the provided answer.
제공된 답변에 대해.
Among the 12 tasks, some of them are generation tasks.
12개의 작업 중 일부는 생성 작업입니다.
And these work well as is with Flan just because it's a decoder-only model.
디코더 전용 모델이기 때문에 Flan과 마찬가지로 잘 작동합니다.
On the other hand, there are some tasks that are classification tasks such as close QA
반면에 Close QA와 같은 분류 작업인 작업도 있습니다.
or sentiment analysis.
또는 감정 분석.
The authors amended the prompt to the models with options to make sure the model will select
저자는 모델이 선택할 수 있도록 옵션을 사용하여 모델에 대한 프롬프트를 수정했습니다.
one of these options as the next-generated token.
다음 생성 토큰으로 이러한 옵션 중 하나를 사용합니다.
Here on the picture, you see that the options are added for sentiment analysis tasks.
여기 그림에는 감정 분석 작업에 대한 옵션이 추가된 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
The authors use Lambda PT as the base model, which is a pre-trained version of the language
저자는 사전 훈련된 언어 버전인 Lambda PT를 기본 모델로 사용합니다.
model for dialogue applications, also from Google.
대화 애플리케이션용 모델도 Google에서 제공합니다.
There are other versions of the Lambda model as Lambda fine-tuned, but these models are
Lambda가 미세 조정된 다른 버전의 Lambda 모델이 있지만 이러한 모델은
further fine-tuned using human feedback and conversation qualities.
인간의 피드백과 대화 품질을 사용하여 더욱 세부적으로 조정됩니다.
But the Flan authors chose to use the pre-trained-only version.
그러나 Flan 작성자는 사전 훈련된 버전을 사용하기로 결정했습니다.
Gamma is a decoder-only model, and it has 137 billion parameters.
감마(Gamma)는 디코더 전용 모델로 1,370억 개의 매개변수를 가지고 있습니다.
It's pre-trained on web documents, dialogue data, and Wikipedia data with a total of 2.8
웹 문서, 대화 데이터, 위키피디아 데이터를 총 2.8개로 사전 학습했습니다.
trillion tokens.
조 토큰.
10% of this training data is in non-English.
이 훈련 데이터의 10%는 영어가 아닌 언어로 되어 있습니다.
To sample the data sets, the authors mix all the data set examples into a single pool.
데이터 세트를 샘플링하기 위해 저자는 모든 데이터 세트 예제를 단일 풀에 혼합합니다.
Then they randomly draw from this pool, and for the sake of keeping every data set well
그런 다음 모든 데이터 세트를 잘 유지하기 위해 이 풀에서 무작위로 데이터를 가져옵니다.
represented in the final training data, they kept the sampling from each data set at 30k,
최종 훈련 데이터에 표현된 각 데이터 세트의 샘플링은 30k로 유지되었습니다.
regardless of how large or small the data set was.
데이터 세트의 규모가 크든 작든 상관없습니다.
Similar to the base model, the input had 1,000 tokens, and the output had 256 tokens.
기본 모델과 유사하게 입력에는 1,000개의 토큰이 있었고 출력에는 256개의 토큰이 있었습니다.
While dealing with shorter input lengths, they use packing to combine multiple shorter
더 짧은 입력 길이를 처리하는 동안 패킹을 사용하여 여러 개의 더 짧은 입력 길이를 결합합니다.
examples into a single sequence for the sake of training.
훈련을 위해 예제를 단일 시퀀스로 만듭니다.
By multiplying the number of gradient steps and the batch size and the input lengths, it
그라디언트 단계 수와 배치 크기 및 입력 길이를 곱하면
looks like Flan is trained on around 257 billion input tokens.
Flan은 약 2,570억 개의 입력 토큰에 대해 교육을 받은 것으로 보입니다.
The authors used AdaFactor as the optimizer, which is similar to Adam in the sense that
저자는 AdaFactor를 최적화 도구로 사용했는데, 이는 Adam과 유사합니다.
it has an adaptive rate, but it's just more memory efficient.
적응 속도가 있지만 메모리 효율성이 더 높습니다.
The training took 60 hours for total of 30k gradient steps with batch size of 8k.
훈련에는 배치 크기가 8k인 총 30k 경사 단계에 대해 60시간이 걸렸습니다.
This slide shows the main results from the paper.
이 슬라이드는 논문의 주요 결과를 보여줍니다.
The graph shows the zero shot performance of different models for data sets from four
그래프는 4가지 데이터 세트에 대한 다양한 모델의 제로샷 성능을 보여줍니다.
held out clusters.
클러스터를 내놓았습니다.
As you can see, Flan, which is shown with the star, always outperforms its base model,
보시다시피 별표로 표시된 Flan은 항상 기본 모델보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
which is shown with the blue dot.
파란색 점으로 표시됩니다.
In many cases, Flan also outperforms GPT-3 and GLAM.
많은 경우 Flan은 GPT-3 및 GLAM보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
GLAM here is a generalist language model with MOE structure.
GLAM은 MOE 구조를 갖춘 일반 언어 모델입니다.
For some tasks such as translation or natural language inference, Flan bridges the gap with
번역이나 자연어 추론과 같은 일부 작업의 경우 Flan은
supervised models as well.
감독 모델도 마찬가지입니다.
Here the supervised models are shown with these vertical gray lines, and they are either
여기에서 지도 모델은 회색 수직선으로 표시되며 다음 중 하나입니다.
based on BERT or T5.
BERT 또는 T5 기반.
In another experiment, Flan compares itself with GPT-3.
또 다른 실험에서 Flan은 자신을 GPT-3과 비교합니다.
As shown in this graph, Flan outperforms GPT-3 in both zero shot and few shot settings for
이 그래프에서 볼 수 있듯이 Flan은 제로 샷 설정과 소수 샷 설정 모두에서 GPT-3보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
some of the tasks.
일부 작업.
But the authors say that these tasks are selected based on the amount of the performance gain
하지만 저자는 이러한 작업이 성능 향상 정도에 따라 선택된다고 말합니다.
that they've had from instruction tuning.
명령 튜닝을 통해 얻은 것입니다.
So this is kind of a best case comparison.
이것이 일종의 최선의 비교입니다.
There are a few ablation studies that I'm going to cover in this presentation.
이번 프레젠테이션에서 제가 다루게 될 몇 가지 절제 연구들이 있습니다.
Number one is the number of clusters.
첫 번째는 클러스터 수입니다.
In this study, the authors add the clusters during the training one by one, from one being
이 연구에서 저자는 훈련 중에 클러스터를 하나씩 추가합니다.
on the leftmost side and seven being on the rightmost side.
가장 왼쪽에 있고 7이 가장 오른쪽에 있습니다.
As you can see, as you add to the number of clusters that has been used during the training,
보시다시피, 학습 중에 사용한 클러스터 수를 추가하면,
the performance of the fine-tuned model improves for the held-out clusters, which are common
미세 조정된 모델의 성능은 일반적으로 유지되는 클러스터에 대해 향상됩니다.
sense, natural language inference, and closed-book keyway.
감각, 자연어 추론, 클로즈북 키웨이 등이 있습니다.
Another thing to observe here is that only after cluster number three, the performance
여기서 주목해야 할 또 다른 점은 클러스터 번호 3 이후에만 성능이 향상된다는 것입니다.
of the fine-tuned models actually are better than the performance of the base models, which
실제로 미세 조정된 모델의 성능이 기본 모델의 성능보다 더 좋습니다.
are here shown with the horizontal dashed lines.
여기에는 수평 점선으로 표시됩니다.
Now, because there is no other experiment on the permutation or the order of these clusters
이제 이러한 클러스터의 순열이나 순서에 대한 다른 실험이 없기 때문에
that are being added, it's not clear that this performance jump is because of this particular
추가되는 항목 중 이러한 성능 향상이 바로 이 특정 항목 때문인지 확실하지 않습니다.
reading comparison cluster that is being added or just because of the number of clusters.
추가되는 비교 클러스터를 읽거나 클러스터 수 때문에.
Another ablation study is about the impact of fine-tuning for different model sizes.
또 다른 절제 연구는 다양한 모델 크기에 대한 미세 조정의 영향에 관한 것입니다.
The authors discovered that the accuracy of the model actually gets worse after fine-tuning.
저자는 미세 조정 후에 모델의 정확도가 실제로 더 나빠진다는 사실을 발견했습니다.
If the model is not large enough here, the cut seems to be somewhere between like 8 billion
여기서 모델이 충분히 크지 않으면 컷은 80억 정도 될 것 같습니다.
and 68 billion.
그리고 680억.
The last ablation study that I'm going to cover with this paper is the role of instructions.
제가 이 논문에서 다룰 마지막 절제 연구는 지침의 역할입니다.
As I mentioned, instruction-tuning is fine-tuning and multiple tasks that are described as instructions
앞서 언급했듯이 명령어 조정은 미세 조정이며 명령어로 설명되는 여러 작업입니다.
in human language.
인간의 언어로.
Now, the authors do this experiment to see if the provided instructions are important
이제 저자는 제공된 지침이 중요한지 확인하기 위해 이 실험을 수행합니다.
or not.
아니면.
They fine-tune other versions of the model, one with just the data sets and no instruction,
그들은 지침이 없고 데이터 세트만 있는 모델의 다른 버전을 미세 조정합니다.
and another one with just the name of the data set and the data itself but no instructions.
또 다른 하나는 데이터 세트의 이름과 데이터 자체만 있고 지침은 없습니다.
And then they do evaluation with or without instructions.
그런 다음 지침이 있든 없든 평가를 수행합니다.
They see that the best combination is when they train the model, they fine-tune it using
그들은 모델을 훈련할 때 가장 좋은 조합이 다음을 사용하여 미세 조정한다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
the human provided instructions and then they also evaluate using instructions.
인간이 지침을 제공한 다음 지침을 사용하여 평가하기도 합니다.
Second paper that I'm going to cover today is T0 from Hugging Face.
오늘 제가 다룰 두 번째 논문은 Hugging Face의 T0입니다.
The idea here is very similar to Flan.
여기서의 아이디어는 Flan과 매우 유사합니다.
The authors do multitask training and zero-shot generalization.
저자는 멀티태스킹 훈련과 제로샷 일반화를 수행합니다.
Similar to Flan, T0 authors also group around 60 data sets into 12 clusters.
Flan과 마찬가지로 T0 작성자도 약 60개의 데이터 세트를 12개의 클러스터로 그룹화합니다.
However, while there is some overlap between the two clusterings, they are different both
그러나 두 클러스터링 사이에는 일부 중복이 있지만 둘 다 다릅니다.
in terms of the data sets that they use and how they group them together.
그들이 사용하는 데이터 세트와 이를 그룹화하는 방법에 관한 것입니다.
In particular, T0 authors have relied on grouping the data sets based on the format
특히 T0 작성자는 형식을 기반으로 데이터 세트를 그룹화하는 데 의존했습니다.
of the output rather than the required scale for doing the task.
작업을 수행하는 데 필요한 규모가 아닌 출력의 규모입니다.
Unlike Flan, T0 authors use cloud sourcing for creating the template of the prompts.
Flan과 달리 T0 작성자는 프롬프트 템플릿을 생성하기 위해 클라우드 소싱을 사용합니다.
They also excluded non-English prompts such as the prompts that use non-English languages
또한 영어가 아닌 언어를 사용하는 프롬프트와 같은 비영어 프롬프트도 제외했습니다.
or those that have maths according in them.
또는 그에 따른 수학을 가지고 있는 사람들.
And finally, they did a pass to remove the prompts with potentially harmful contents.
마지막으로 잠재적으로 유해한 콘텐츠가 포함된 프롬프트를 제거하는 작업을 수행했습니다.
After this prompt collection, they released a public pool of prompts that at the time
이 프롬프트 수집 후에 그들은 당시에 사용되었던 프롬프트의 공개 풀을 출시했습니다.
of writing, it covered like 177 data sets with more than 2000 prompts.
글을 쓰면서 2000개 이상의 프롬프트가 포함된 177개의 데이터 세트를 다루었습니다.
The authors use language model adopted version of T5 as their base model.
저자는 T5의 언어 모델 채택 버전을 기본 모델로 사용합니다.
This is because the T5 is trained on Bertostal denoising objective and the authors argue
이는 T5가 Bertostal 노이즈 제거 목표에 대해 훈련을 받았고 저자가 주장하기 때문입니다.
that language model objective, which is introduced in LM adopted variation, makes it more useful
LM 채택 변형에 도입된 언어 모델 목표는 이를 더욱 유용하게 만듭니다.
for instruction tuning.
명령 튜닝을 위해.
This model has encoder, decoder architecture with 11 billion parameters.
이 모델에는 110억 개의 매개변수가 있는 인코더, 디코더 아키텍처가 있습니다.
Similar to Flan, T0 authors randomly drew training samples from a mixed pool of data
Flan과 마찬가지로 T0 작성자는 혼합된 데이터 풀에서 훈련 샘플을 무작위로 추출했습니다.
sets.
세트.
But they kept the number of samples for each data set at 500K rather than 30K.
그러나 그들은 각 데이터 세트의 샘플 수를 30K가 아닌 500K로 유지했습니다.
The input and output token lengths here again are similar to Flan with a thousand input
여기서도 입력 및 출력 토큰 길이는 1,000개의 입력이 있는 Flan과 유사합니다.
and 256 output tokens.
256개의 출력 토큰.
T0 is trained with total of 250 billion tokens with batch size of a thousand tokens.
T0는 배치 크기가 1,000개 토큰인 총 2,500억 개의 토큰으로 훈련됩니다.
Similar to Flan, Edda Factor Optimizer was again used for training T0.
Flan과 유사하게 Edda Factor Optimizer가 T0 훈련에 다시 사용되었습니다.
This slide shows the main results of the paper.
이 슬라이드는 논문의 주요 결과를 보여줍니다.
The figure compares the zero shot performance of T0 with its base model and as well as three
그림은 T0의 제로 샷 성능을 기본 모델과 비교한 것입니다.
different sizes of GPT-3.
다양한 크기의 GPT-3.
And four different task clusters are used here as held up tasks.
그리고 여기서는 4개의 서로 다른 작업 클러스터가 보류 작업으로 사용됩니다.
Because this is a zero shot evaluation, the author reports the results both for the base
이는 제로샷 평가이기 때문에 작성자는 베이스에 대한 결과를 모두 보고합니다.
model and T0 on all the prompts for each data set.
각 데이터 세트에 대한 모든 프롬프트에서 모델 및 T0.
And that's why you see multiple blue or green dots.
이것이 여러 개의 파란색 또는 녹색 점이 보이는 이유입니다.
They do not do any cherry picking or they do not report any average or median.
그들은 체리 따기를 하지 않으며 평균이나 중앙값을 보고하지 않습니다.
This is in contrast to all the other data points from GPT-3 which is a single number
이는 단일 숫자인 GPT-3의 다른 모든 데이터 포인트와 대조됩니다.
coming from the GPT-3 paper.
GPT-3 논문에서 나온 것입니다.
As you can see, T0 always outperforms the base model.
보시다시피 T0은 항상 기본 모델보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
Another noticeable result is that T0 outperforms GPT-3 in all natural language understanding
또 다른 눈에 띄는 결과는 T0가 모든 자연어 이해에서 GPT-3보다 뛰어난 성능을 보인다는 점입니다.
tasks, even though it's 11 times smaller.
작업은 11배 더 작더라도 마찬가지입니다.
In an abolition study, the authors studied the effect of the number of prompts during
폐지 연구에서 저자는 폐지 기간 동안 프롬프트 수의 효과를 연구했습니다.
training on the performance of the output model.
출력 모델의 성능에 대한 훈련.
The one with zero prompts is the base model because it hasn't been trained with any prompts.
프롬프트가 없는 모델은 어떠한 프롬프트로도 훈련되지 않았기 때문에 기본 모델입니다.
And the one shown with green is the T0 model with an average of almost eight prompts per
녹색으로 표시된 것은 T0 모델로, 1회당 평균 거의 8개의 프롬프트가 표시됩니다.
data set.
데이터 세트.
As you can see, when you add to the number of prompts, the performance of the model improves.
보시다시피 프롬프트 수를 늘리면 모델 성능이 향상됩니다.
And in many cases, even adding one single prompt is enough to improve the performance
그리고 대부분의 경우 단일 프롬프트를 추가하는 것만으로도 성능을 향상시키기에 충분합니다.
of the model significantly.
모델의 크게.
Similar to the previous results, T0 authors here report the results for all the prompts
이전 결과와 유사하게 여기의 T0 작성자는 모든 프롬프트에 대한 결과를 보고합니다.
and that's why there is an interval with the rectangle in between and the rectangle is
그래서 그 사이에 직사각형 사이에 간격이 있고 직사각형은
the middle 50% of the performance.
성능의 중간 50%.
As you can see, when you have fewer number of prompts, let's say one or five, even though
보시다시피 프롬프트 수가 적은 경우 1개 또는 5개라고 가정해 보겠습니다.
the median performance has improved in comparison to zero prompt, there is still a big or large
프롬프트가 0인 경우와 비교하여 중간 성능이 개선되었으나 여전히 크거나 큰 문제가 있습니다.
variance that you can see among different prompts.
다양한 프롬프트에서 볼 수 있는 차이.
For some tasks, having many prompts hurts the performance.
일부 작업의 경우 프롬프트가 많으면 성능이 저하됩니다.
As you can see in the graph, this can be because of the varying quality among the prompts that
그래프에서 볼 수 있듯이 이는 프롬프트 간의 품질이 다양하기 때문일 수 있습니다.
are used.
사용됩니다.
So it's not always the case that the more you add to the number of prompts, the better
따라서 프롬프트 수에 더 많은 것을 추가할수록 더 좋은 것은 아닙니다.
the results are going to be.
결과는 될 것입니다.
This slide provides an overview comparison of T0 versus Flan.
이 슬라이드는 T0과 Flan의 개요 비교를 제공합니다.
Both of these models use instruction tuning to improve the zero shot performance of language
이 두 모델 모두 명령어 튜닝을 사용하여 언어의 제로샷 성능을 향상시킵니다.
models.
모델.
Flan uses a decoder only model as base model versus T0 uses an encoder, decoder model that
Flan은 디코더 전용 모델을 기본 모델로 사용하는 반면 T0은 인코더, 디코더 모델을 사용합니다.
is 11 times smaller.
11배 더 작습니다.
In fact, in an abolitionist study, Flan's experiment showed that instruction tuning
실제로 폐지론자 연구에서 Flan의 실험은 명령 조정이 다음과 같은 것으로 나타났습니다.
for a smaller model can degrade the performance which doesn't match what T0 has done in the
더 작은 모델의 경우 T0가 수행한 것과 일치하지 않는 성능이 저하될 수 있습니다.
experiments.
실험.
Flan's dataset includes 10% non-English data versus T0 has excluded all the non-English
Flan의 데이터세트에는 10%의 비영어권 데이터가 포함되어 있는 반면 T0은 모든 비영어권 데이터를 제외했습니다.
dataset and data from their training dataset.
데이터세트와 훈련 데이터세트의 데이터.
You can see this in their experimentation results when Flan is reporting results for translation
Flan이 번역 결과를 보고할 때 실험 결과에서 이를 확인할 수 있습니다.
tasks and in those types it beats the performance of the supervised models versus translation
이러한 유형의 작업에서는 지도 모델과 번역의 성능을 능가합니다.
tasks are not included in T0 results.
작업은 T0 결과에 포함되지 않습니다.
Both of these papers have published their datasets and Flan V2 is a newer version of
이 두 논문 모두 데이터 세트를 발표했으며 Flan V2는 Flan V2의 최신 버전입니다.
Flan and in fact it also includes the p3 dataset from T0.
Flan은 실제로 T0의 p3 데이터세트도 포함합니다.
The two papers are also different in how they train the model for the held-up task.
두 논문은 보류 작업에 대한 모델을 훈련하는 방법도 다릅니다.
Flan trains a single model per held-up task versus T0 trains one model for three held-up
Flan은 보류된 작업당 단일 모델을 훈련하는 반면 T0은 3개의 보류된 작업에 대해 하나의 모델을 훈련합니다.
tasks together and that's a better estimation of the model's generability to a diverse set
작업을 함께 수행하면 다양한 세트에 대한 모델의 생성 가능성을 더 잘 추정할 수 있습니다.
of unseen tasks.
보이지 않는 임무.
Other than a brief discussion section in T0, the two papers do not compare themselves
T0의 간략한 토론 섹션 외에는 두 논문을 비교하지 않습니다.
with one another but both of them report results for a natural language inference task when
하지만 둘 다 다음과 같은 경우 자연어 추론 작업에 대한 결과를 보고합니다.
they compare themselves against GPT-3. Based on the results, they have a very similar performance
그들은 자신을 GPT-3과 비교합니다. 결과에 따르면, 그들은 매우 유사한 성능을 가지고 있습니다.
for most of the natural language inference datasets.
대부분의 자연어 추론 데이터세트에 적용됩니다.
There is only one dataset, the commitment bank from SuperGrowl, T0 significantly outperforms
단 하나의 데이터세트만 있습니다. SuperGrowl의 약속 은행인 T0이 훨씬 더 뛰어난 성능을 발휘합니다.
Flan, giving that both models are trained on around 250 billion tokens, it's partly
Flan은 두 모델 모두 약 2,500억 개의 토큰에 대해 교육을 받았다고 가정합니다.
possible that the Lambda PT model is under-trained and because of that it has a similar performance
Lambda PT 모델이 충분히 훈련되지 않아 유사한 성능을 가질 가능성이 있습니다.
to T0 while having a much larger number of parameters.
훨씬 더 많은 수의 매개변수를 가지면서 T0으로 변경됩니다.
There is a more recent paper that mixes the two training datasets to get the best instruction
최상의 지침을 얻기 위해 두 개의 훈련 데이터 세트를 혼합한 최신 논문이 있습니다.
tuning results at scale. This paper also trains Flan T5 and Flan POM but the next paper that
결과를 대규모로 조정합니다. 이 논문에서는 Flan T5와 Flan POM도 훈련하지만 다음 논문에서는
I'm going to cover takes a different direction rather than just scaling up the fine tuning.
나는 단지 미세 조정을 확대하는 것보다 다른 방향을 취하는 것에 대해 다룰 것입니다.
Let's talk about Lima or less is more for alignment from MetaAI.
MetaAI의 정렬을 위해 Lima 이하에 대해 이야기해 보겠습니다.
The hypothesis of this paper is that models have learned the knowledge during pre-training
본 논문의 가설은 모델이 사전 훈련 중에 지식을 학습했다는 것입니다.
and alignment will only teach them the style or the format they need for interacting with
정렬은 상호작용에 필요한 스타일이나 형식만 가르칠 뿐입니다.
users. With this hypothesis, only limited instruction fine tuning or limited instruction
사용자. 이 가설을 사용하면 제한된 명령 미세 조정 또는 제한된 명령만
tuning data is required to teach models to produce high quality outputs.
고품질 출력을 생성하도록 모델을 교육하려면 데이터 조정이 필요합니다.
To test this hypothesis, Lima focuses on creating only 1,000 carefully curated prompts that
이 가설을 테스트하기 위해 Lima는 신중하게 선별된 프롬프트 1,000개만 만드는 데 중점을 둡니다.
have diverse input styles but a unified output style in the format of a helpful assistant
다양한 입력 스타일을 가지고 있지만 유용한 보조자 형식의 통일된 출력 스타일을 가지고 있습니다.
AI. Lima authors select their prompt data from different sources.
일체 포함. 리마 저자는 다양한 소스에서 프롬프트 데이터를 선택합니다.
The first source is StackExchange which has over 170 different exchanges. StackOverflow
첫 번째 소스는 170개 이상의 다양한 거래소가 있는 StackExchange입니다. 스택 오버플로
is one of the famous ones, for example. For each StackExchange, the authors sample 200
예를 들어 유명한 것 중 하나입니다. 각 StackExchange에 대해 저자는 200개를 샘플링합니다.
questions. They selected the questions with the highest scores but also questions that
질문. 가장 높은 점수를 받은 질문을 선택했지만,
were self-contained in the title without any overflow to the body.
본문에 오버플로 없이 제목에 자체 포함되어 있습니다.
They also selected top answers for each selected question. As long as the answer, the top answer
또한 선택한 각 질문에 대한 상위 답변도 선택했습니다. 답변이 있는 한, 상위 답변
had at least plus a positive 10 score or upwards. Finally, they excluded answers that didn't
최소한 플러스 10점 이상을 받았습니다. 마지막으로 그렇지 않은 답변은 제외했습니다.
match the helpful assistant style. For example, if the answer was too short or too long or
도움이 되는 어시스턴트 스타일과 일치하세요. 예를 들어 답변이 너무 짧거나 너무 길거나
if it was written in the first person format or if the answer was not self-contained referencing
1인칭 형식으로 작성되었거나 답변이 독립적인 참조가 아닌 경우
to other posts for some additional information, they excluded all that. And finally, they removed
추가 정보를 얻기 위해 다른 게시물에 대해서는 모든 내용을 제외했습니다. 그리고 마침내 그들은 제거했습니다
the links and images from the responses. Vikiha was the second source of data that the authors
응답의 링크와 이미지. Vikiha는 저자가 작성한 두 번째 데이터 소스였습니다.
used for prompt creation. They sampled 200 articles with a two-level sampling method. With
프롬프트 생성에 사용됩니다. 그들은 2단계 샘플링 방법으로 200개의 기사를 샘플링했습니다. 와 함께
this method, they first sampled one category out of the existing 17 categories of articles
이 방법을 사용하여 기존 17개의 기사 카테고리 중 하나의 카테고리를 먼저 샘플링했습니다.
and then from within that category, they sampled an article to make sure the whole sample
그런 다음 해당 카테고리 내에서 기사를 샘플링하여 전체 샘플이
count that they have is as diverse as it can be. They used the article title as the input prompt
그들이 가지고 있는 수는 가능한 한 다양합니다. 기사 제목을 입력 프롬프트로 사용했습니다.
and the body as the response. Similarly, they did some processing to remove the images and
그리고 몸이 반응합니다. 마찬가지로 그들은 이미지를 제거하기 위해 일부 처리를 수행했으며
links and other tags from the response.
응답의 링크 및 기타 태그.
Reddit dataset was a third data source that Lima authors used for creating their training
Reddit 데이터 세트는 Lima 작성자가 교육 생성에 사용한 세 번째 데이터 소스였습니다.
dataset. Since Reddit is mostly used for the purpose of entertaining rather than being
데이터세트. Reddit은 대부분 재미보다는 오락의 목적으로 사용되기 때문에
actually helpful, top voted answers could be sarcastic or funny, but not necessarily in
실제로 도움이 되고, 최고 투표를 받은 답변은 냉소적이거나 ​​재미있을 수 있지만 반드시 그런 것은 아닙니다.
the format of helpful assistant style. To avoid such answers, the authors only manually selected
도움이 되는 어시스턴트 스타일의 형식입니다. 그러한 답변을 피하기 위해 저자는 수동으로만 선택했습니다.
examples from the top most voted posts and they only limited that to two subreddits. Ascended,
가장 많이 투표된 상위 게시물의 예를 보여주며 이를 두 개의 하위 레딧으로만 제한했습니다. 승천,
which is a QA in format of QA and R prompts, which is a subreddit that someone provides a premise
누군가가 전제를 제공하는 하위 레딧인 QA 및 R 프롬프트 형식의 QA입니다.
of a fictional story and then the users are encouraged to creatively complete that story.
허구의 이야기를 만들어 사용자가 그 이야기를 창의적으로 완성하도록 권장합니다.
As the final step of dataset creation, the authors manually wrote prompts. They used two
데이터 세트 생성의 마지막 단계로 작성자는 프롬프트를 수동으로 작성했습니다. 그들은 두 개를 사용했습니다
different groups of authors for training versus testing to make sure evaluation remains
교육을 위한 다양한 작성자 그룹과 평가가 유지되는지 확인하기 위한 테스트
where and there is no bias or contamination. The authors also wrote responses for the prompts
편견이나 오염이 없는 곳입니다. 작성자는 프롬프트에 대한 응답도 작성했습니다.
in the training set. They answered the questions in the style of helpful assistant AI with some
훈련 세트에서. 그들은 유용한 보조 AI 스타일로 질문에 답변했습니다.
acknowledgement of the question followed by the answer, arguing that this format would help the
질문을 인정한 후 답변을 하며, 이 형식이 도움이 될 것이라고 주장합니다.
model to form train of thoughts. To further diversify the training set, they selected a single
생각의 기차를 형성하는 모델. 훈련 세트를 더욱 다양화하기 위해 그들은 단일을 선택했습니다.
example from 50 natural language generation tasks such as summarization and included that in their
요약과 같은 50가지 자연어 생성 작업의 예를 만들고 이를
training dataset as well. For training, the authors used Lama with 65 billion parameters as the base
훈련 데이터 세트도 마찬가지입니다. 훈련을 위해 저자는 650억 개의 매개변수가 있는 Lama를 기본으로 사용했습니다.
model and the input size of 2000 tokens. They trained the model on 1000 collected examples and
모델 및 입력 크기는 2000 토큰입니다. 그들은 수집된 1000개의 예시를 바탕으로 모델을 훈련시켰고
batch size of 32 for 15 epochs because there wasn't enough data to have a single epoch. But they
단일 에포크를 갖기에는 데이터가 충분하지 않았기 때문에 15개의 에포크에 대해 배치 크기를 32로 했습니다. 그러나 그들은
also manually selected the model checkpoint between the 5th and 10th epochs based on the evaluation
또한 평가를 기반으로 5번째와 10번째 신기원 사이의 모델 체크포인트를 수동으로 선택했습니다.
on the 50 held out deficits rather than only using the last checkpoint after 15 epochs. They
50일에 15 에포크 이후 마지막 체크포인트만 사용하는 대신 적자를 버텼습니다. 그들
also used the special end of turn token to differentiate between the users and the assistant's
또한 사용자와 어시스턴트를 구별하기 위해 특별한 턴 종료 토큰을 사용했습니다.
role. They used Adam W as the optimizer, which is very similar to Adam except for the fact that
역할. 그들은 Adam W를 최적화 도구로 사용했는데, 이는 다음과 같은 점을 제외하면 Adam과 매우 유사합니다.
they've corrected the way the weight decay is implemented. They used dropout of the
그들은 가중치 감소가 구현되는 방식을 수정했습니다. 그들은 드롭아웃을 사용했습니다.
residual networks. They started with rate 0 at the bottom level and linearly increased at the
잔여 네트워크. 그들은 가장 낮은 수준에서 비율 0으로 시작하여 선형적으로 증가했습니다.
dropout rate 2.5 for the last layer. To set the effectiveness of Lama, the authors asked human
마지막 레이어의 드롭아웃 비율은 2.5입니다. 라마의 효율성을 설정하기 위해 저자는 인간에게 물었습니다.
evaluators to compare its output and to compare its output to the average output of the
평가자는 출력을 비교하고 출력을 평균 출력과 비교합니다.
other models for giving prompt and specify if they prefer Lama's response or the other model's
프롬프트를 표시하고 Lama의 응답을 선호하는지 다른 모델의 응답을 선호하는지 지정하는 다른 모델
response or if they think it's a tie. Since this is a subjective, very subjective task, the
응답하거나 동점이라고 생각하는 경우. 주관적이고 매우 주관적인 작업이므로,
authors also measured the inter-annotator agreement over some randomly selected annotations and
저자는 또한 무작위로 선택된 일부 주석에 대해 주석자 간 일치도를 측정했으며
they showed that the inter-annotator agreement is really high. Human evaluators compared Lama with
그들은 주석자 간 합의가 정말 높다는 것을 보여주었습니다. 인간 평가자들은 라마를 다음과 비교했습니다.
these 5 models on one-on-one settings. The results summary is showed in the right-hand side graph
이 5가지 모델을 일대일로 설정하세요. 결과 요약은 오른쪽 그래프에 표시됩니다.
and it shows that while comparing Lama with Alpaca on 74% of the cases, the results are
74%의 경우에 라마와 알파카를 비교한 결과는 다음과 같습니다.
comparing Lama with Alpaca on 74% of the cases, the human evaluators either preferred Lama
74%의 사례에서 라마와 알파카를 비교했을 때 인간 평가자는 라마를 선호했습니다.
or they assumed it's a tie. This is impressive because the Alpaca model, while has the same
또는 그들은 그것이 동점이라고 생각했습니다. 이것이 인상적인 것은 알파카 모델과 동일하면서도
number of parameters, is trained on 52 times more data. Another impressive finding is that in 43%
52배 더 많은 데이터에 대해 학습되었습니다. 또 다른 인상적인 결과는 43%에서
of the cases, the human evaluators preferred Lama over GPT-4 or they claimed that the two
이 경우 인간 평가자들은 GPT-4보다 Lama를 선호했거나 두 사람이
were in a tie. In another evaluation, the authors used GPT-4 as the evaluator and the comparison
동점이었습니다. 또 다른 평가에서 저자는 GPT-4를 평가자로 사용하고 비교를 수행했습니다.
results had overall a similar trend. However, GPT-4 preferred answers from larger models more
결과는 전반적으로 비슷한 경향을 보였습니다. 그러나 GPT-4는 더 큰 모델의 답변을 더 선호했습니다.
often. Interestingly enough, in 90% of the cases, GPT-4 actually preferred Lama's response
자주. 흥미롭게도 90%의 경우 GPT-4는 실제로 Lama의 반응을 선호했습니다.
over its own response. In an appellation study, the authors experimented with the quality
자신의 반응보다. 명칭 연구에서 저자는 품질을 실험했습니다.
and diversity of the training data. To do so, they find in the 7 billion version of the model
그리고 훈련 데이터의 다양성. 그렇게 하기 위해 그들은 70억 버전의 모델에서 찾습니다.
with 2,000 examples. So they fixed the number of examples, but the sources of these examples
2,000개의 예시가 있습니다. 그래서 그들은 예시의 수를 정했지만 이러한 예시의 출처는
were coming from different data sets. Then they asked GPT-4 to grade the helpfulness of
다른 데이터 세트에서 나왔습니다. 그런 다음 GPT-4에 다음의 유용성을 평가해 달라고 요청했습니다.
each of these trained models, with six being the highest and one being the lowest helpful.
훈련된 각 모델은 6개가 가장 높고 1개가 가장 유용합니다.
For each data set, five examples from its testing split were randomly selected for this evaluation.
각 데이터 세트에 대해 테스트 분할에서 5개의 예가 이 평가를 위해 무작위로 선택되었습니다.
As you can see in the bar chart, the first data set is coming from Vikiha.
막대 차트에서 볼 수 있듯이 첫 번째 데이터 세트는 Vikiha에서 나옵니다.
This data set has high quality but low diversity because it's a highly moderated data set, hence
이 데이터 세트는 고도로 조정된 데이터 세트이기 때문에 품질은 높지만 다양성은 낮습니다.
the high quality, but all the prompts are in the format of how to hence the low diversity.
품질은 높지만 모든 프롬프트는 다양성이 낮은 방법에 대한 형식으로 되어 있습니다.
The second data set here is unfiltered stack exchange because it has many different topics,
여기의 두 번째 데이터 세트는 필터링되지 않은 스택 교환입니다. 주제가 다양하기 때문입니다.
it has high diversity, but since it's unfiltered, it has low quality.
다양성은 높지만 필터링되지 않았기 때문에 품질이 낮습니다.
The last column, which is the best performing one, is filtered stack exchange, which means
가장 성능이 좋은 마지막 열은 필터링된 스택 교환입니다.
it has both high quality and high diversity, and that's why it has the best performance.
높은 품질과 높은 다양성을 모두 갖추고 있기 때문에 최고의 성능을 발휘합니다.
This experiment confirms that the importance of both quality and diversity of the data
이 실험은 데이터의 품질과 다양성 모두의 중요성을 확인시켜줍니다.
is crucial for instruction tuning. Thank you everyone for listening to me so far.
명령어 튜닝에 매우 중요합니다. 지금까지 제 이야기를 들어주신 모든 분들께 감사드립니다.
Next, Hossein will talk about reinforcement learning with him and feedback.
다음으로 호세인과 함께 강화학습 및 피드백에 대해 이야기해보겠습니다.